# ANDREA VALLA

SOLUTION ARCHITECT - FULL STACK DEVELOPER

# Professional summary

Experienced full stack programmer: developed enterprise level and scalable web applications. Experience in both client and server side programming.

Background in all steps of software engineering including analysis, design, coding, testing and implementation.

Enjoy learning and staying current on bleeding edge technology, systems, libraries and frameworks. Grown with shells, linux user since '95')

## Technical skills

Frontend React, Redux, Apollo, Gatsby, Gulp, Sass, Webpack Backend NodeJs, Express, Koa, GraphQL, AspMVC, Php Mobile iOS, basic knowledge of android development Testing Jest, Cypress
Languages Javascript, C#, Swift, Php, Objective-C
Databases MongoDb, SqlServer, MySql, Sqlite, Oracle
Business Intelligence SSIS, SSRS, Pentaho Kettle, Cubejs
Operating systems Linux, Unix, MacOSX, Windows
Devops Docker, Cl/CD on Github and GitLab
Cloud Azure, AWS

## Professional experience

FULL STACK DEVELOPER :: FEB 2022 - TODAY BRANDSDISTRIBUTION.COM :: TURIN. ITALY

Developed integrations between BDroppy (a dropshipping application) and external ecommerce platforms (e.g. shopify, squarespace, wix, ekm).

Typescript, NodeJs, React, Jest, Redux, Moleculer, Redis, MongoDb

CTO AND CO-FOUNDER: MARCH 2018 - JAN 2022

AGILE FACTORY - POLITECNICO DI TORINO SPINOFF COMPANY :: TURIN, ITALY

Developed MES solution for SMEs. It helps manufacturing industries to accelerate their production processes, showing data in realtime. Connected to IIOT devices via OPC-UA or MQTT and communicates with customer's ERPs via ETL.

NodeJs, GraphQL, React, Jest, Cypress, Apollo, Redux, MongoDb, Redis, Github, Docker, mqtt, OPC-UA, S3, Lerna, Kettle, Sonarqube

FULL STACK DEVELOPER :: JUNE 2015 - MARCH 2018

INDUSTRIAL CLOUD - POLITECNICO DI TORINO SPINOFF COMPANY :: TURIN, ITALY

Developed web applications for manufacturing industry, from analysis to customer deployments and updates.

NodeJs, React, Elastic Search, Mysql, Php

FULL STACK DEVELOPER:: SEPTEMBER 2010 - JUNE 2015

INTESA SANPAOLO :: MONCALIERI (TURIN), ITALY

Developed web interfaces, ETL and reports on Microsoft environment.

.net, Javascript, EF, Dapper, SqlServer, SSRS, SSIS, ASPMVC, WebForms, jQuery, KnockoutJS, Twitter Bootstrap, Sharepoint

DEVELOPER AND SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR: SEPTEMBER 2003 - SEPTEMBER 2010

REPLY SPA :: TURIN, ITALY

Consultant on different kind of projects, from development to system administration, on Linux, Unix and Microsoft environments.

.net, WebForms, Javascript, Linux, Unix, BMC ITSM

UNIX SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR :: JULY 2002 - JULY 2003

GLOBAL VALUE SERVICES :: TURIN, ITALY

System and application management on some FCA websites. HPUX and custom web applications

#### Informations

Birth date 9 august 1980, Turin, Italy Phone +39 335 82 30 421 Email valla.andrea@gmail.com Website https://avalla.github.io

# Languages

Italian Mother tongue English Fluent German Beginner

#### Education

M101JS MongoDB for NodeJs developers :: 2014
M102 MongoDB for DBAs :: 2014
Unix and Linux administration course
Immaginazione e Lavoro, Torino, IT :: 2002
High school diploma Galileo Ferraris, Torino, IT :: 2002

## Other projects

### Malingering:: 2020

Used to test the effectiveness of psychological tests. It was developed with Gatsby, React, Redux, FaunaDb and deployed on Netlify, using web and functions.

## Sphere Contents:: 2020

IPs Browser for movies, serials, books and comics. Developed with Gatsby, React, Redux, Algolia, and Wordpress, deployed on Netlify (only web). Content managers configure contents on Wordpress panel.